In this video I'm going to show you how to create a character sheet like this,
as well as a location one, so that you can put these image references into C-Dance 2.0,
along with your storyboard, which will help you achieve a much higher level of consistency
in your videos to create something like this.
So in this video I'm basically going to be going through some of the videos that I've posted on my
Instagram using character location sheet storyboard. Just walk you through like the process of
what I've been experimenting with, and then at the end of the video I'm going to just go through
like how exactly I would do it in the moment live, so you can look at the process and take some
pieces from it and go out and do it yourself. Right, so to start with I'm going to be just looking
at this video here, so this is purely just a storyboard into C-Dance 2.0.
So if we just look at the prompt here, it's just create a 4x4 storyboard and then kind of
describing the theme and then it's coming up with the shots here and it creates something like this
and then to create the video literally just putting it into C-Dance 2.0, use the storyboard
image one as a reference image to make 4 arcane style, I'm prompting like nothing here to achieve
this. Using C-Dance 2.0 720p 15 seconds, you can also use C-Dance fast, I found does pretty decent
job. I do it at 720p, I think that's just the best of like both in terms of decent enough quality
and saving credits and if we just look at like whether it's adhering to the storyboard, it does a
pretty decent job like that's them dropping in, the backdrop is obviously different but it's them
dropping in, skateboard there, then him, then her, then all three, then him, then it's gone back to him
so it hasn't, it's missed this here, I would say that it's probably that bit there, something around
there, so it's kind of, actually you know that bit was, that's that there, then it's gone to three there
and so you can see it's about, it's adhered to it like 70-80% which I think is pretty solid
basically uploading a storyboard like this, like I'm pretty impressed with this and to make the
final video and what I've discovered is you do kind of need to piece them together a little bit
so what I done is is generated four or five versions which is usually what I do and kind of
piece them together like I put the ending like from that one with it but the problem that I found
with this one because this was kind of the beginning of the process is that there was no
character sheet, no location sheet because the whole generation is not perfect and I want to piece
things together, I need each sort of separate generation that I've done here to be as consistent
as possible, so I started thinking about like creating character sheets and location sheets for
a different video but I'm just going to walk through some of my findings with character sheets
and how to do those, but firstly in terms of like finding characters I find mid-journey is by far
the best, like you can pay for a subscription for $10 to get access to like the explore page here
because you can simply just go on like guy, find a character, there are just so many just ways to
find characters on mid-journey and it's just easy you can see the prompt and what I do is find a
character, either use the prompt or remix the prompt, regenerate in mid-journey or take over to like
nanobanana 2 or GPT to then edit the image, mid-journey is not very good at editing, it's good at
generating characters but then maybe I want like the character to be you know the close to be
different color or something slightly different and I'll use other models but if I've just got the
reference image like that it's easy for me to take that into GPT and nanobanana to fix it
and so the next video I'm looking at is this one here so this has got like a character sheet,
didn't have a location sheet because at this point I hadn't just really needed to use a location
sheet even though I just said that I needed one because I'm talking retrospectively because the
thing is with this one in terms of location because every shot is there moving in one location
but it's moving through different shots it means that like you can get away with not having
a location sheet and the thing it was kind of the same for this one so this is using a character
sheet and then it's actually just using a prompt rather than a storyboard which I'm going to show
at the end you can do either or it doesn't really matter and I'll talk about why you might do one or
the other so again this is the character sheet for this one so this is kind of like what I developed
off the back of these ones here because the thing is about these ones this was for a completely
different video is when we look at a character sheet like this this was just what a GPT image 2.0
is producing but like you don't need all of these images so I discovered is this like what is the
point of having like that image and that image lonely basically doing the same job and I had seen
people generating character sheets like this on Instagram so just naturally went for one like this
but then you have to ask yourself the question is everything on this needed is this writing needed
here no and so is it just wasted space and just would it be better to have a more condensed
character sheet which will go through later on in the video not to say that it doesn't work a
character sheet like this it absolutely does I think this is just more for just looking pretty if
I'm honest rather than actually being the best character sheet to achieve the best level of
consistency but if we look here this so the I uploaded the character sheet here and then this is
the prompt here so this is now not using basically a storyboard uploaded this is just using a description
of the shot which works kind of the same anyway because if I wanted to just turn this into storyboard
I'll just take this into chat GPT and ask it to create me a storyboard image and it did a
pretty this is the original shot that I use really like this opening shot the problem I had
looked his headphones are gone straight away and this was the video where I basically realised
need location sheets because like I was having to regenerate the video with that sort of prompt
because it didn't have a storyboard I feel like the model then really struggled to really understand
like the location or he understood the location but wasn't able to maintain it so not having
just using a character sheet not having a storyboard not having a location sheet
was able to keep character consistency relatively well and it kind of adhere to the shots that I was
describing as you can see here so I did take this shot as well because I felt like I could match
that in and then I pieced them together as well from about two or three video generations but
what I originally was doing was like as you can see here taking the character sheet the original
starting image some shots like in between the video as well which you could do instead of a
location sheet like if you generate one video and you like the location then just take some
screenshots from that video and then upload them as reference images because if you look here that's
very similar to the original one there and that that's a different generation and then there we
go we've got this part here it's a bit all over the place but as you can see the location is
fairly similar to what I had before and so yeah basically after this video I was like okay just
having a character sheet doesn't work on the basis that these videos don't one shot multiple
generations going to be need to be produced so you need a character sheet a location sheet
potentially a storyboard but maybe not necessarily a storyboard because you can just prompt the
shots and it just still does a good job so the next video where kind of this all kind of fit
it together to some degree and was developing then the character sheet and location sheet was this video
here
so this is using a character sheet a location sheet no storyboard because I wanted to basically see
whether I could achieve like good results you know without the storyboard this time having understood
actually maybe it can just be done with the character sheet a location sheet so this was the
character sheet here still a bit too much going on in my opinion more condensed than the other one
but at this point like I was starting to realize like again is this necessary I don't think so
just looks good but isn't actually necessarily needed and so then this is the location sheet again
too much going on here retrospectively saying this like just because I was just prompting
GPT and M2.0 to create a location sheet and I think this is maybe what like a traditional location
sheet looks like I'm not like a film there I don't have no experience in this but like is this
necessary for the model is it reading this text probably not does it need to know these colors
probably not but anyhow just went forward with using like character sheet and location sheet
and it still does like a decent job weird shit happens as you can see there but each generation is
like fairly consistent in the shots that I'm asking for in the prompt so if I just go
into the prompt here so if you can see here this one's a bit difficult to read but you see like
shot one one to two seconds two to four so it's describing each of the shots at the different
seconds and you'll find that every generation is going to be doing that and so like I was going
to say this later but this is why I also run them at 720 because I'm just trying to understand
whether the prompts delivering shots that I want and then what I'll do is basically so like it's
always producing this shot in every video and that shot and then this running sequence that's a nice
shot so then what I end up doing is basically cutting loads of them together so it's like
I find different jumping shots you'll see here right but like when I put the music on the timeline
I was like I want more shots in the beginning like you see of his sort of like cape thing and so all
I basically then went and done was essentially just changed the prompt and was like I'd go back
into the chat GPT and say I need more like close cutting prompts in the beginning it produced all
these ones here which then just gave me a few extra shots to add at the beginning
and then all these shots here like these will be from different video so like this one that one
that one this is the same video that's a different video that's a different video so because I've
got the character sheet and location sheet I'm able to cut from different videos and it looked
pretty good and I said like I don't like these character location sheets in terms of their fanciiness
but they still do the job right I haven't tested extensively enough to know how this is a good
example actually of like the video not here into the the sheet like the rope here look goes from
here to here with this little arc thing here that arc thing there the ropes coming there but the
video is happening so quick you you never have noticed that like until I've just pointed out
and it's doing it across that it was doing it across all of the generations anyway so I wasn't too
bothered even though you could probably look at the roof here and see that like actually the different
generations have slightly different roof very very small details but as I said when you're
quick cutting a video doesn't make a difference but this kind of was what opened my eyes up to maybe
I needing a better location sheet essentially like that is not good enough location sheet because
it's just not enough details which led me to sort of experimenting and trying to find like again
a more stripped down location sheet like this and then this was also the character sheet that
I had basically gone okay how can we create a new character sheet get sort of all the fluff in
its front side back face shot clothing I think that's probably all you need in my opinion in most
cases and then I was trying to do something similar with a location sheet but it wasn't it just
wasn't prompts weren't listening to I wanted like as you can see like that shot and that shot is
the same pointless pointless pointless pointless and even when I was trying to get it to prompt to
not do that I was still doing you might say actually just that might be good enough I also
don't know whether it's better this is not realistic it's in this weird style is it better to do
it in a realistic style but then does it cause it the model to do weird stuff this one here a bit
more complex but like is that needed is that needed is that needed is that needed probably not I'm
still trying to figure out what's the best location sheet to have like wide view top down view maybe
some close angles I think it depends on the video you're making but one thing I've learned is the
more complex your location is the harder it is to maintain continuity and as I was talking about
earlier you know I was talking about this video here this is progressing through a city so I can
cut the shot easily this is progressing through a city this is in one location it's not progressing
through somewhere so you understand every shot needs to basically look like it's from the same
building and then the last example that I'm just going to go through before we go how to do it
is this site basketball this was quite difficult
so this was using storyboard, character sheet and location sheet so a little bit different than
the last one just showing you that you know this could work as well and for this one we're just
going for like a really stripped down character sheet like not even front back sides but actually
found it to be a pretty good job here still worked really really well location sheet was difficult
because the basketball lines and in the video it was really struggling with just maintaining
the location sheet continuity haven't figured out location sheet continuity yet so anyone has
any suggestions please suggest them storyboard similar style did pretty good job but like adhering to
like opening shot then close together then sort of joling against each other whatever you want to
call it and then some shots at the end and this was again just piecing together the different
videos here as you can see done that like close in shot there they are
but then it was doing lots of kind of weird shit like this and so this one was like I just
show you what it actually looks like all the time man this was very much like piecing together
like some some shots I liked or some such I just made shorter
so like if I just extend you some of these clips right you'll see like that's the original
so all I've done is take that original one cut it to here if I show you this one this will be
completely different as well again look doing weird shit so I'm just taking the best moments
I'll show you this one as well so it's across like I found on average you need about four or five
generations like that love that didn't like that bit again weird shit there but again it's just
I can make this look good by just cutting the best shots from each of the generations
and then I played around with just the music here like boom boom boom boom at this point I'm using
the music as well to like figure out what cuts I want to do how long to make the video
and and that's kind of the kind of the theme across all the generations is cutting them together
on the timeline and using the best shots if I actually just look at the prompt for this one
again no prompt here so just simply creating the video from the sequence of shots which it does
a good job you know you can watch the video and see you know even this is a slightly different
storyboard starting shot then facing together then then battling each other then some shots in
hoop so like I'm giving the video a clear direction that it does follow every time it will just
mess up a number of different shots but there every generation I found has shots that are usable
it's just then you taste making and picking the ones that fit together so the storyboard method
is really good I could probably take this storyboard and actually just write it as a prompt as well
if I wanted to I could actually take all of these like text bit here and write as a prompt and not
use a storyboard I just find that the storyboard gives you a method gives you a good visual of like
what you're getting where you can't see on the prompts and so if you wanted to like save credit
on the video I would always probably generate the storyboard because then you can go yes that is
what I want you might actually look at the story and go you go shot three four five six seven eight
all kind of look the same do I want to put in some different shots in there like a wider one you know
and so you can better plan the shots with the storyboard because you can visually see them
and then you can then alter the image prompt to then regenerate the storyboard to hopefully save
your credits and get you exactly what you want or let's say you generate the video and you're
like actually I need like more of this type of shot like I talked about with this example here
I didn't use a storyboard but I used that same principle of like watching the video and go well I
want more shots at the beginning so I'm going to prompt for more shots at the beginning again it
doesn't matter whether you use prompt or a storyboard both methods work as I have shown throughout
this video so it's really just up to you to decide which method you want to use and so now
just going to go through how I would go about coming up with ideas for this this is live in the
flesh so it the idea could be shit I'm just going to put my hands up I'm not going to just like I
have not pre-generated anything here this is just doing it raw and so what we're going to do I'm
going to go into the explore page on mid journey so we're going to pick one I've used this character
recently let's just take this character for example and I'm going to show you a process for coming
up with ideas that hopefully will just open your eyes up to a different way to do it so I'm going
to check GPT you can use chat GPT you can use claw doesn't matter we're going to drag in the image
reference and what I'm going to do here is I'm going to describe what I'm trying to do and this is
why prompts don't really matter because if you understand the process you understand the intention
behind what you're doing and you can describe it you don't need prompts like chat GPTing Club
very good at coming up with prompts so I need some help coming up with some ideas for a video I'm
trying to create a quick cutting 15 second video using cdance 2.0 this is the character that I
want to use please can you give me 10 different like little synopsis that's not a word of different
scene stories for me to review so then I can then go forth with this idea that is the shittiest
voiced prompt I've ever done in my life I'm just going to show you like how easy this is to do
so now we've got 10 ideas here we've got world's tricks instructor inspection coffee incident
everyone freezes because someone spilled coffee in the academy hallway so now yeah it's it's giving
me the monster students panic as a giant monster tell the academy everyone runs except him you
try and be sure to close the whistle once and the monsters immediately line up be all right let's
just try this one right so I'm going to copy this I don't know how ever this is going to work because
the monsters are all going to be different but we'll just go with this one anyway because I'm just
showing you the process so I want to go with number six the monster academy please can you
build me out a detailed image prompt that's going to generate a storyboard for this it should be
four by four it's going to be a 15 second video so they're obviously going to be roughly 12 to
16 shots in there and let me know if you've got any questions all right so this is actually just
giving me the image from that I didn't want that I wanted to prompt but we'll check the image anyway
all right so this is actually that's actually not done too but I just want to say can you see how
just kind of rough around the edges that works but actually do you know what let's just let's just
take this image like I'm happy with that the storyboard there I'm now going to create the character
sheet and location sheet it obviously has created the location there I could create the location sheet
before I do the storyboard if I've got a specific idea in mind or I just use the storyboard to come
up with the location which it's done here you can do either or it's all depends on like what
your starting idea is if you're like actually I know where exactly I want this monster thing to happen
and I've already got an existing image reference then use that as said you can do the storyboard
first you can do the location sheet first you can do the character sheet first it doesn't matter
but let's just go forth with that and I am going to ask for the location sheet I would just
upload this is image reference but I don't think I'd need to see as I'm in here please can you use
this image as a reference image and now create a location sheet of this area top down shot front
side back any details that are needed for the location to maintain continuity very ship problem
again I want to just show you how easy it is for you to just figure this out yourself in terms
of what prompts to use because as I've shown to all of my examples like the videos still work with
all sorts of different character sheets location sheets and it's really just about you know
the idea and you piecing it together in in the final part because I've made I think all of my
videos pretty decent by just picking the right shots and the right music and them coming out good
right okay here is the location sheet that's actually not too bad I'm happy with that again
there are some unnecessary details here so like in an ideal world you develop your own location
prompt that works for you rather than doing it the messy way like I'm doing it because I don't
know whether we need color palette architectural style but if we look at that image and compare it
to what it's done off this I think it's done a pretty good job there of using that as an image
reference so we'll take that and then last but not least we're going to create a character sheet
please can you create me a character sheet of this character front side back close up the face
and the clothing right looking at the character sheet what is this done for me pretty good see like
this is this will be good enough I'm actually very happy that's a very good job there just looking
at continuity here trials look good boots look good I don't know what this is here but we'll take
you anything in your clothing where it has small details is usually where you're going to get
problems so like this here I would definitely want a shot like that on the character sheet because
otherwise it will get that wrong that is kind of too far away I in my opinion on the sheet for
it to know what that is but honestly I think we are good to go now and so I'm just going to use
runway because I've got some credits to use so we're going to go c launch 2.0 I'm going to go
fast because it's cheaper 16 by 9 15 seconds if you want to save more credits you can also go down
to 480 I've been absolutely rinsing credits or I've been actually generating at 480 because for
me and my use case all I'm doing is putting the video here a lot of people have said on my
Instagram are the differences between 480 and 720 and 1080 and 4K are all different but here's the
thing it doesn't matter what res model you're using if you're using a storyboard it is still going
to follow the storyboard yes the output might not be as good but you might just use it as a test so
I might just say I'm going to generate this storyboard in 480 because I simply just want to see
how the shots look like together how does the idea feel in a video okay this looks good I'm happy
with it I'm maybe now going to go to 720 and when I'm going to go to 1080 because I'm confident
these are the shots that I want if I'm like hmm I don't like this shot I don't like this shot or
do you know what this idea just doesn't work right so if we go back into here we're going to now
upload all of my image references in here so we've got image 1 character sheet image 2 the location
sheet image 3 the storyboard and I am just going to put in the most basic ask prompt here just to
show you that anybody can do it use image 1 which is the character sheet and image 2 which is
the location sheet to generate the storyboard in image 3 and I'm going to generate this I'm going
to generate a few of these just just to save time just to see how each of them changes so I've
generated 3 or 4 here you know I wouldn't do this if it was the first time I'm doing it and also
if you're conscious of credits again just generate the one idea but for sake of just this video
because 47 minutes in to recording this fuck my life I'm going to have to wait for these
generate and so while I wait for these to generate just in terms of like credit usage I use a number
of different platforms because I'll just be transparent I have part and access to to car long
social I get free credits across runway, artless, magnificent, it's still not actually paid for because
it was cheap I've got a good deal in terms of like which do I think is the best honestly they're all
very similar they all are just aggregators they all are just using the same models that have APIs
and pulling in those models some platforms sort of have fancier features but then they don't really
work that well and so if all you need access to is the image models and the video models you can
really use any platform to be honest they will all do the same job in that respect and so I would
recommend just go and looking at the pricing of all of them and just seeing whether they've got
any deals and just evaluating how much do image generations and video generations cost across
the different platforms I this is a whole different video in itself but that's what I would do you're
not really getting more for your money aside from how much it costs per video image when it comes to
like the other other platforms features some might people might disagree with that but as someone
that just purely does image and video generation if you want node based included in that
magnificent has that or you might want to use a separate one for that like weevee runway also has
a node based system and so like you know there are there are small nuance differences between each
platform but in my opinion as somebody that uses you know a number of different platforms just
look at the pricing and then just go for the what that is most affordable for you right so these
videos are starting to generate okay what are these going to look like so just off the bat here
not too bad continuity between each of the buildings let's just watch this one first
hey I don't think that that's too bad we've got the same we've got like multiple versions of the same
guy which I guess is a I might sort of would go back into the prompt and I would maybe just add
something into the prompt here to
um you can you see how like easy it was to generate a video like that like pretty decent
let's just look at the other ones now just for content how well is it like maintained what I've
asked for
so I love some shots from this one okay see like that part was sick
so I would 100% take that into the final video so like this video here I would probably take
that establishing shot I think it's better this one is good that one is good this one is decent
is let if we switch there to there and then switch to this one boom I like that one that's a good
final one so it's really about you just watching the videos and picking the best shots like
and and making sure like you maintain see like that weirdness head that shot that part is going
but in terms of location and how it's handled like the cut that the him is the main character
is great as you you can see that like
the actual people are all the same here so again I might try and prompt that to get rid of that but
I'm pretty happy with how that's come out and you can see it literally took no time for me to do
that I had my character and I could have picked any of these ideas you know and and I might go
back through these and go actually I want to do this or if I don't like any of these ideas I say
give me 10 more or if I've actually got an idea that would probably help and so you can really
just start with something or you can start with nothing you just need the character and I really
am happy that came out how it did because this is the bare bones most basic way of doing it and it's
still did as an alright result in my opinion if I wanted to make this better I would start with
my character and already have an idea and describe that idea in as much detail as possible get more
detail here I would probably spend more time on this storyboard here you can see here look that
the characters are different here and here but not really so I would maybe you just go back and
try and work on that the monsters are also a little bit different might want to put in a
actual monster character sheet as well that would probably make sense if they all look the same
so I would get the continuity could probably generate an image of all different people like
generate like an image with like 50 different peak faces on and it would probably do better and
that way you could get all of the continuity working before you've even gone through the video
location sheet the area looks bigger in the video but it's it's nailed all of this pretty well
so that I think is the video wrapped up this has been a long one but I really wanted to go into
depth and just show you the the process that I've been going through just be super transparent
with it just so that you can see actually it's not as difficult as you might think there are
loads of different methods and ways of of doing it but actually getting the end result all just
relies on you cherry picking and taste making the right shots from your video generation so that
you've got good consistency and continuity across them and then finding just good music to match
the vibe I hope it's been valuable if you have any questions drop in the comments more than happy
to do some more follow up videos on this but if not have a nice week and I'll see you in the next
video